sentara.com 2005-02-06

# Sentara Healthcare - Privacy Statement

**Web Site Privacy Statement**

To Review Sentara's Integrated Notice of Privacy Practices, [click here.]

Sentara Healthcare is dedicated to protecting the privacy of Web site users. As a user of our Web site, you will have access to comprehensive information that will help you to understand certain illnesses, find accurate, in-depth details about local services and providers, and take charge of your personal health.

Sentara wants you to feel as comfortable as possible when visiting our Web site and using the services it offers. This Privacy Statement tells you what information we collect, how we protect it and what choices you have about how that information is used. Your privacy refers to any information that is collected about you while interacting with Sentara.com.

Sentara may revise these terms and conditions at any time. We will clearly display changes if and when they occur, so that you will always know what information is being collected, how it is being used, and under what circumstances it is being disclosed. Please review this document periodically to be aware of any changes posted, because your continued use of the site will indicate your approval of all changes.

We urge you to read the following Privacy Statement so that you will understand both our commitment to you and your privacy, and how you can participate in that commitment.

****

**Collection of Information**  
By using this web site, you consent to the collection and use of your information as discussed in this section. 

Generally, personal information is not requested or collected. However, some features offered on Sentara.com require you to register first and provide basic, personal information.

The first time you register, you will be asked to choose a user name and password and provide basic information. Record your password and protect it for future use. If you forget your password, you can reset or change your password online. You have access to your information collected during the registration process, and may choose to update or change your information at anytime with the I.D. and password that you created.

Sentara also collects information that you volunteer through electronic forms such as "Contact Us" and "Care Options". For some "transactions" on Sentara.com, certain information is required to process your request. When information is requested from you, Sentara attempts to clearly indicate which information is required and which information is optional. Information collected to process specific transactions is only used for the specific service that you have chosen. However, throughout Sentara's Web site you are offered opportunities to receive related or general information in the future from Sentara. In cases like these, Sentara will ask for your "permission" to contact you (see next section for more).

Overall, your information is used to maintain accuracy in Sentara's customer files, improve the content of Sentara.com, and enhance Sentara products and services.

****

**How Sentara Uses Your Information**  
Sentara does not sell, trade, rent or share your personal information to organizations outside Sentara Healthcare and its affiliate companies unless required to do so by legal, judicial or governmental proceedings.

Sentara reserves the right to store and use any information you voluntarily provide for marketing and communications specific to Sentara without additional notice. However, Sentara will make every effort to get your permission ("opt-in") for Sentara to contact you in the future. You will also have the option of respectfully requesting that Sentara not contact you ("opt-out").

The information collected about the domain name of the server from which you are visiting is collected in aggregate and used to determine the number of visitors to our site, sources of traffic, and other key indicators of Web site usage to create a better experience for visitors to Sentara.com. This information does not identify you personally.

****

**Sponsoring Organizations**  
Sentara works with various organizations to improve and enhance its Web site. Where Sentara has entered into a relationship with such an organization, Sentara requires the respective organization to fully disclose their business practices including a privacy statement. Sentara encourages you to read the disclosure statements of any such organization so that you are aware of any differences from its own disclosure statements.

****

**Cookies**  
In some instances, Sentara stores a cookie -- a small computer file -- on your computer to make it easier for you to use various Web services on our Web site. Sometimes, a cookie will be required in order to establish and maintain a secure session so that you can request data and conduct business transactions without having to re-enter information. "Cookies" vary in the amount of time they are valid depending on the specific application or service.

****

**Your Responsibility**  
Please note that you are responsible for taking all reasonable steps to ensure that no unauthorized person shall have access to your user name or File. It is your sole responsibility to (1) control the dissemination and use of your user name; (2) to authorize, monitor and control access to your login and password; and (3) to promptly notify us of any need to deactivate your user name.

By registering with Sentara.com, you grant Sentara and all other persons or entities involved in the operation of our Web site the right to receive, transmit, monitor, retrieve, store and use your Personal Information. This includes information that may be privileged and confidential under applicable state and federal laws, in connection with the operation of our Web site and our maintenance of your File. 

Sentara.com includes links to other sites. If you choose to visit another site, Sentara cannot assume responsibility for its content or information handling practices. We encourage you to review each site's privacy policy prior to entering into transactions with the respective site. 

****

**Sentara's Responsibility**  
Sentara wants your Personal Information to remain as secure as reasonably possible. Your Personal Information is stored securely. All of our staff must abide by our Privacy Policy and those who violate it are subject to disciplinary action, up to and including termination. 

Sentara will store your Personal Information in databases for a reasonable time period to ensure that the information remains current. We will update our database periodically to ensure that it remains current, and will purge your Personal Information when we believe it is no longer valid or current. 

****

**Security**  
Sentara has taken the appropriate precautions to protect information sent over the Internet. Sentara's Web site has security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. Sentara employs strict security measures to safeguard transactions that take place over the Internet. Any personal information is stored in a secure database and sent and received by a secure, encrypted Internet channel wherever possible.

****

**Your Email**  
If you contact us by email, your message will be forwarded to our employees or agents best able to address your questions and concerns. Please note that email transmissions over the Internet with Sentara.com are not encrypted.

Non-encrypted Internet email communications are not completely secure or private and may be intercepted and viewed by other Internet users, without your knowledge and permission, while in transit to us.

To protect your privacy, please do not use email to communicate confidential information. Please choose to contact Sentara by telephone for matters that require greater privacy and security.

****

**Feedback**  
If you have comments or suggestions, please contact us by selecting "About this Web site" from the available options. 

Please read our Web site User Agreement.

[Last updated January, 2005]

* * *

Home | About Sentara | Peninsula | News & Events | Staying Healthy  
Find a Doctor | Hospitals | Facilities & Services | Job Opportunities  
Health Plans | Search & Site Map | Web Resources | Contact Us

* * *

Copyright © 2005 Sentara Healthcare. All Rights Reserved.  
Please read our User Agreement.
